

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







Program Director seeking roles in Program Management, Project Management, Agile Methodology, Digital Transformation, Cloud Computing, Delivery Management, Requirement Gathering, Workflow Analysis, Selenium, JIRA, GIT, DevOps

Current Designation: Program Director Total Experience: 17 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Current Company: Mondee Pvt Ltd (Meta Minds) Highest Degree: MS/MSc(Science) [Computers]

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

Pref. Location: Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance Role: Program Mar

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Program Director, Program Manager, Program Management, Project Management, Agile Methodology, Digital

Transformation, Cloud Computing, Delivery Management, Requirement Gathering, Workflow

Analysis.Selenium.JIRA.GIT.DevOps

Verified : Le Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

#### Summary

17 Years of experience in IT

- \* 7 Years of Client engagement roles in North America
- \* 6 Years of Agile Coach experience for enterprise customers end to end, reported progress to all stakeholders through Sprint Burn-Down Reports, Iteration Burn-Down Reports, and velocity target updates, Long term stories

  \* Strong knowledge on QA Tools such as ALM (Starting from Test Director), many Opensource Test Tools, Automation ROI
- \* Implemented the entire release process across all the departments Engineering, SaaSOps, Services, Support with the

of the tools JIRA, Smartsheet, GIT, NetSuite, Trello for about 13 teams with 8 projects across distributed teams which are in Serbia, California, Birmingham, Hyderabad respectively

\* Strong knowledge in JIRA in creating Workflows caters entire eco system of the company, sync to other tools like Smartsheet, GIT, Portfolio, Agile story map, Tempo, All Reports and other integrations to Trello, Google sheets etc.

## **Work Experience**

Mondee Pvt Ltd (Meta Minds) as Program Director Mar 2018 to Till Date

Working as Program Director (reporting to CEO) and handling Delivery responsibilities from Offshore for Tech, Dev,

- API Teams.

  \* Championed cultural changes and collaborated with other teams on plans and techniques for accelerating and advancing the organization's transformation.
- \* Successfully Transformed Waterfall to Agile Methodology for about 60 members team across USA and India.
- \* Successfully delivered a world class product Travel CRM to the Travel industry which is an independent solution replacing Salesforce, Ring Central and other third-party applications
- \* Completely handled the Agile transformation through JIRA with Admin capabilities by providing a powerful workflow which caters all the audience such as Technology, QA, Business, Product Support, API teams respectively
- \* Directly worked with CEO and provided the Dashboards of Agile of KANBAN which gives complete visibility on the Resources day to day, Week work life.
- \* For QA, worked with TestRail team and defined complete process of JIRA-TestRail integration.
- \* Using Tempo (Timesheet Tool to JIRA), integrated with JIRA and defined complete Framework which gives visibility of each resources of the company in terms of Productivity and Non-Productivity.

  \* Performed the role of Technical Account Manager for API Business and created process in
- https://developer.trippro.com which caters the customers across the Globe includes Asia, Europe, North America \* Using JIRA API, Tempo API, Test Rail API created a third-party application for Mondee which provides a solid report
- gives complete visibility of entire Delivery Ecosystem.

  \* Provided Resource visibility to CEO which helped in taking decisions in Rating system of Appraisal system
- \* Worked in integration of Process for the acquisitions such as RockeTrip, CTS etc.
- \* Experience with Kibana in Data Visualization transforming the data of Search metrics to NOC Team which helps in handling the API Customers
- r Complete control on Reporting related to Dev, QA, NOC, Business Team, Top Leadership in any format/tool.
- \* Involved in API, Functional Automation Contribution to DevOps



# **Important**

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

#### SAP as Sr. Manager, Program Management & QA Feb 2015 to Mar 2018

Worked as Agile Coach, Program Manager, SCRUMMaster & QAManager roles

- \* Championed cultural changes and collaborated with other teams on plans and techniques for accelerating and advancing the organization's transformation.
- \* Mentored teams, leading them to be self-directed with strong accountability, decision making, conflict resolution and transparency.
- \* Transformed 13 Teams from Waterfall to Agile methodology acting Agile Coach role for about 2 years which includes 150 Engineering employees
- \* Trained 13 teams in Agile (SCRUM Masters, Business Analysts, Managers and Executives on Agile values) where teams

are spread across Serbia, US, India Territories

\* Created Callidus Agile document which describes checklist, guidelines, procedures for each role in Agile which must be

followed as a Callidus Cloud Engineering Employee

- \* Created Compliance Metrics in an enterprise level for each team which every team needs to make sure they follow.
- \* Created a Dashboard for Top Management till CEO which describes Status, Quality, Releases Health, Agile Adoption (Transformation Metrics). This dashboard gets live data from JIRA with php, High charts using REST Services exposed by Atlassian.
- \*Created best practices in JIRA for all the teams to follow right from Support team to Engineering Team
- \* Successful implementation of SAFe and acted role of Release Train Engineer from mid-2016 and completed 4 releases
- \* so far.
- \* Acting as JIRA Admin for Callidus Cloud for creating Workflows, users, groups, Notifications on status,
- \* Acting as Internal Auditor and Engineering representative for External audits and Surveillance audits for ISNS to get ISO Certification
- \* Acting as SCRUMMaster role for 4 projects which are platform teams such as SSO, Connector, Reporting & Analytics
- \* and API Services teams
- \* Working as Program Manager role for 7 projects to get the reports from JIRA which will be visible till CEO of Callidus Cloud
- \* Experience of creating critical workflows for the teams between Services, Support, Engineering, SaaS Ops teams respectively
- \* Working currently to implement DevOps for all Agile teams across CallidusCloud.
- \* Work experience of the tools such as Trello, Aha, Portfolio, Trello, User Story map, Google Docs integration with JIRA
- \* Wrote Agile FAQ's which can be utilized by the individual teams to help them successful as Self-Organized teams.

### Alliance Global Services as Project Manager

Dec 2013 to Feb 2015

Worked as QAManager for IDEXX Laboratories Project for 4 teams at Customer place by visiting customer place.

- \* Used Rally to implement entire ecosystem
- \* Changed the way of Quarterly awards from individual levels to Agile level in terms of Team levels
- \* Contributed towards and oversaw the transition from Scrum to Kanban.

^ Back to Top

## **Education**

PG: MS/M.Sc(Science) (Computers) from Andhra University in 1999

^ Back to Top

### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
JIRA	
SAP	
GIT,DevOps	

^ Back to Top

# **Affirmative Action**

#### **Work Authorization**

Category: **General**Physically Challenged: **No** 

Job Type: Permanent
Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.